<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tmux on Heru Setiawan</title>
    <link>https://herusetiawan.id/tags/tmux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tmux on Heru Setiawan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 08:23:15 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://herusetiawan.id/tags/tmux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Save Tmux Session</title>
      <link>https://herusetiawan.id/posts/how-to-save-tmux-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 08:23:15 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://herusetiawan.id/posts/how-to-save-tmux-session/</guid>
      <description>Hi folks,
When you start using tmux, it will always create a new session. We can say that session is tmux main feature. Session can contains multiple windows and panes. It depend on your needed.
The interesting thing is you can create multiple tmux sessions. Usually, every session only related to one project. For example you have 2 tmux session. The first is “laravel” session contains 2 panes. First pane is used to open vim editor and the second pane is used to run the laravel app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Deal With Tmux Session</title>
      <link>https://herusetiawan.id/posts/how-to-deal-with-tmux-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 19:04:46 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://herusetiawan.id/posts/how-to-deal-with-tmux-session/</guid>
      <description>Hi folks,
When you start using tmux, a new session will always appear. We can say that a session is tmux main feature. A session can contain multiple windows and panes. It depend on your need.
The interesting thing is you can create multiple tmux sessions. Usually, every session only related to one project. For example you have 2 tmux sessions. Session “laravel” contains 2 panes. The first pane is used to open vim editor and the second pane is used to run the laravel app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Tmux</title>
      <link>https://herusetiawan.id/posts/an-introduction-to-tmux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 21:38:29 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://herusetiawan.id/posts/an-introduction-to-tmux/</guid>
      <description>What is Tmux? Tmux is a terminal multiplexer. It&amp;rsquo;s allow you to open multiple terminal sessions inside a single terminal window and easily switching between them. Tmux also allow you to split terminal into multiple windows. Means, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to open multiple tabs in terminal when you have multiple task. Trust me, tmux is very effective and will save your time!
Session, Window and Pane When you use tmux, terminal tab is definitely deprecated.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>